Guide to the John Reinerman Family Land Documents, 1857-1888 MS 021
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
John Reinerman Family Land Documents
1857-1888
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Roy, Max
MS 021
0.1 Linear Feet (11 documents)
Land deeds and agreements relating to the tract of land in Harris County granted to John Reinermann, dating from 1857-1888.
Biographical Note
The Reinermann family has a long relationship with Rice University, and income from the John Reinermann tract of land in Harris County currently provides scholarship funding for many Rice students.
Scope and Contents
Land deeds and agreements relating to the tract of land in Harris County granted to John Reinermann, dating from 1857-1888. Other families invovled in the land ownership include the Bethje, Brunner, Quensell, and Roy families.
Access Restriction
This material is open for research.
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dr. Max Roy, 1984.
Related Material
See also MS 339 - Papers of Reinermann, Sandman, Bethje, and Quensell families, available at Woodson Research Center.
Index Terms
Subjects
Land grants
Places
Texas -- Harris County
Subjects (Persons)
Roy, Eliza; Brunner, Bertha; Quensell, Louise; Reinermann, Frederic; Bethje, C. L.; Bethje, Eliza; Roy, Max
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University
- Series I: Documents 1847-1860, 11461 (Folder 1)
  - Certificate of land grant to John Reinermann, April 28, 1847, 11466
  - Deed from Harris County to James Bailey and Jethro McGee, December 3, 1857, 11465
  - Field notes from Survey of Reinermann Estate, February 28, 1860, 11464
  - Deed from C.L. Bethje to William & Louise Quensell, March 15, 1860, 11463
  - Deed from Frederic Reinermann to William and Louise Quensell, March 15, 1860, 11462
- Series II: Documents 1877-1886, 11454 (Folder 1)
  - Field notes of survey of land granted to John Reinermann, Jan. 25, 1867, 11460
  - Agreement between C.L. Bethje and William and Louise Quensell, Jan. 10, 1868, 11459
  - Agreement between Bertha Brunner and Eliza Bethje and William and Louisa Quensell, Feb. 25, 1878, 11458
  - Deed from Louisa & William Quensell to Eliza Roy, July 15, 1881, 11457
  - Agreement between Bertha and Anton Brunner and Eliza Bethje regarding will of C.S. Bethje, Jan. 4, 1882, 11456
  - Deed from William and Louisa Quensell to Eliza Roy, Jan. 23, 1886, 11455